<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="introduction" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:ns52="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:ns5="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:ns4="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:ns3="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Introduction</title>

  <section xml:id="introduction-overview">
    <title>Overview</title>
    
    <para>Interacting with HTTP-based services armed only with the relatively
    low-level classes provided by the .NET Framework is possible, but often
    leads to your having to repeat the same boilerplate code over and over again
    as well as evolve your own set of helper methods to translate your objects
    to and from the text-based world of HTTP requests and responses into the
    object-based world of .NET consumers of HTTP services. The Spring.Rest
    project contains the RestTemplate helper class which allows developers to
    focus on the issues of delivering business value in their applications
    rather than focusing on low-level plumbing concerns.</para>

    <para><classname>RestTemplate</classname> provides higher level methods that
    correspond to each of the six main HTTP methods that make invoking many
    RESTful services a one-liner and help to enforce REST best practices. It is
    conceptually similar to other template classes in Spring, such as
    <classname>AdoTemplate</classname> and <classname>NmsTemplate</classname>.
    It's behavior can be customized by providing callback methods and
    configuring the <interfacename>IHttpMessageConverter</interfacename>s used
    to marshal objects into the HTTP request body and to unmarshall any response
    back into an object.</para>

    <para>This documentation describes how to use the
    <classname>RestTemplate</classname> and its associated
    <interfacename>IHttpMessageConverter</interfacename>s.</para>

    <para>Spring.NET REST Client Framework supports the following .NET
    Frameworks : <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>.NET 2.0</listitem>

        <listitem>.NET Client Profile 3.5 and 4.0</listitem>

        <listitem>.NET Compact Framework 3.5</listitem>

        <listitem>Silverlight 3.0 and 4.0</listitem>

        <listitem>Windows Phone 7.0 and 7.1</listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>

    <note>RestTemplate has been available in the Java version of the Spring
    Framework for many years and has recently been adapted to use proper .NET
    idioms.</note>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="introduction-migrating-1.0">
    <title>Migrating from 1.0</title>

    <para>
      Some API changes were made after 1.0. The file, 'breaking-changes.txt', 
      in the root directory of the distribution contains the full listing of 
      breaking changes made for 1.1.
    </para>
    
  </section>

  <section xml:id="introduction-licence">
    <title>License Information</title>

    <para>Spring.NET REST Client Framework is licensed according to the terms of the Apache License,
    Version 2.0. The full text of this license are available online at <ulink
    url="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0">http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0</ulink>
    . You can also view the full text of the license in the license.txt file
    located in the root directory of the distribution.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
